DIFFERENZA TRA OPTICA E DENSE FLOW

link: https://stackoverflow.com/questions/11037136/difference-between-sparse-and-dense-optical-flow:
-Sparse optical flow works on features(edges,corners etc). Dense optical flow is designed to work on all the pixels. 
The advantage of the first is that it is generally faster while the second can give estimates for more pixels than the first.
-Sparse optical flow - Lucas-Kanade method computes optical flow for a sparse feature set (e.g. corners detected using Shi-Tomasi algorithm). 
Dense optical flow - Gunner Farneback's algorithm computes the optical flow for all the points in the frame. This is explained in 
"Two-Frame Motion Estimation Based on Polynomial Expansion" by Gunner Farneback in 2003(http://www.diva-portal.org/smash/get/diva2:273847/FULLTEXT01.pdf).
-Sparse flow is the same as point tracking, dense flow consists of vectors over the video, indicating estimates of motion of fixed positions.


######################################################################################################
cuda::OpticalFlowDual_TVL1 
https://www.ipol.im/pub/art/2013/26/article.pdf

ALGORITMO:
usato per calcolare il dense flow
TV-L1 optical flow(I0, I1, u^0, τ, λ, θ, ε, Nmaxiter, Nwarps)
output u è l'immagine contenente il flow risultante

PARAMETRI INPUT:
• τ is the time step of the numerical scheme. Chambolle shows [1] that the numerical scheme
converges for values of τ < 0.125. Empirically, its value can be set to 0.25 for a faster convergence

• λ is the attachment parameter. This is the most relevant parameter, which determines the
smoothness of the output. The smaller this parameter is, the smoother the solutions we obtain.
It depends on the range of motions of the images, so its value should be adapted to each image
sequence.

• θ is the tightness parameter. It serves as a link between the attachment and the regularization
terms. In theory, it should have a small value in order to maintain both parts in correspondence.
The method is stable for a large range of values of this parameter.

• ε is the stopping criterion threshold used in the numerical scheme, which is a trade-off between
precision and running time. A small value will yield more accurate solutions at the expense of
a slower convergence.

• η is the downsampling factor. It is used to downscale the original images in order to create the
pyramidal structure. Its value must be in the interval (0, 1).

• Nscales is used to create the pyramid of images. If the flow field is very small (about one pixel),
it can be set to 1. Otherwise, it should be set so that (1/η)
N − 1 is larger than the expected
size of the largest displacement. See our article on Horn–Schunck optical flow [3] for further
details on this and the η parameters.

• Nwarps represents the number of times that are computed per scale.
This is a parameter that assures the stability of the method. It also affects the running time,
so it is a compromise between speed and accuracy.

VALORI DI DEFAULT:
τ		time step 			0.25
λ 		data attachment weight 		0.15
θ 		tightness 			0.3
ε 		stopping threshold 		0.01
η 		zoom factor 			0.5
Nscales 	number of scales 		5
Nwarps 		number of warps 		5



######################################################################################################
video data layer




######################################################################################################
######################################################################################################
cose da aggiungere 
-challenge
-obiettivi futuri 
	piu dati
	accoppiati con gli oggetti
	sequenza temporale per distinguere esempio open e close